<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>RA</title>
    <link>https://rusdy.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on RA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.149.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rusdy.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Codebuff: The AI Command Line Copilot That Will Revolutionize Your Workflow</title>
      <link>https://rusdy.com/posts/codebuff-ai-command-line-coding-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rusdy.com/posts/codebuff-ai-command-line-coding-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tired of switching between your terminal and IDE just to get AI help with coding? What if I told you there&amp;rsquo;s an AI coding assistant that lives directly in your command line, understands your entire project, and can make wholesale changes across multiple files with a single natural language command?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meet &lt;strong&gt;Codebuff&lt;/strong&gt; – the terminal-native AI coding assistant that&amp;rsquo;s changing how developers interact with AI tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-makes-codebuff-different&#34;&gt;What Makes Codebuff Different?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;its-built-for-the-terminal&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Built for the Terminal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike other AI coding tools that require you to leave your workflow, Codebuff operates entirely within your terminal. No more context switching, no more copying and pasting between applications. Just pure, uninterrupted development flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Time for What Matters with AI Help</title>
      <link>https://rusdy.com/posts/finding-time-what-matters-ai-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rusdy.com/posts/finding-time-what-matters-ai-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Been coding for 23 years now. Love it, always have. But man, sometimes the boring stuff just eats up all my time. Then I found Claude Code, and wow – suddenly I can build way more cool stuff AND actually have dinner with my family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Claude Code Interface&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://rusdy.com/claude_code.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem-too-much-time-on-boring-stuff&#34;&gt;The Problem: Too Much Time on Boring Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look, after all these years, setting up databases and writing the same login code for the hundredth time isn&amp;rsquo;t fun anymore. It&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip; tedious. I&amp;rsquo;d rather spend that time:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40Hz Gamma Focus: Cara Mudah Otak Kekal Fokus</title>
      <link>https://rusdy.com/posts/40hz-gamma-focus-cara-otak-fokus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rusdy.com/posts/40hz-gamma-focus-cara-otak-fokus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pernah tak rasa susah nak fokus bila buat kerja atau baca sesuatu? Baru mula sekejap, terus fikiran melayang. Sebenarnya, otak kita ada gelombang tertentu yang kawal cara kita berfikir. Salah satunya ialah gelombang gamma 40Hz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Gelombang 40Hz&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://rusdy.com/gelombang_40hz_neon.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apa-maksud-40hz-gamma&#34;&gt;Apa Maksud 40Hz Gamma?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otak manusia bergerak dengan &amp;ldquo;gelombang elektrik&amp;rdquo;. Ada gelombang untuk tidur, ada untuk tenang, ada untuk fikir laju. Gelombang gamma 40Hz pula selalu muncul bila kita fokus, belajar benda baru, atau cuba ingat sesuatu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaraText: Simplifying Translation Management in Laravel Applications</title>
      <link>https://rusdy.com/posts/laratext-laravel-translation-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rusdy.com/posts/laratext-laravel-translation-package/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Managing translations in Laravel applications can be a tedious and error-prone process, especially when dealing with multiple languages and dynamic content. Enter &lt;strong&gt;LaraText&lt;/strong&gt; by Eduardo Lázaro — an elegant package that revolutionizes how we handle internationalization in Laravel projects by combining simplicity, automation, and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-translation-challenge&#34;&gt;The Translation Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional Laravel translation management often involves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating and maintaining separate language files for each locale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manually writing translation keys that are hard to read and maintain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time-consuming process of translating content across multiple languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping track of missing translations across different language files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LaraText tackles these challenges head-on with an intuitive approach that makes translation keys both &lt;strong&gt;useful and readable&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing Model Ownership in Laravel with the Ownable Package</title>
      <link>https://rusdy.com/posts/laravel-ownable-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rusdy.com/posts/laravel-ownable-package/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Need a clean, reusable solution to handle ownership dynamics in your Laravel app? Enter &lt;strong&gt;Laravel Ownable&lt;/strong&gt; — a polished package by Abdullah Sowailem that lets any Eloquent model own any other model. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re managing users and tasks, vendors and products, or documents with dynamic custodians, this package brings clarity, flexibility, and auditability to ownership logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a refreshed overview for your blog, incorporating up-to-date insights from the official repository (updated August 10, 2025).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pos Pertama Saya</title>
      <link>https://rusdy.com/posts/pos-pertama/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 20:45:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rusdy.com/posts/pos-pertama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;selamat-datang-&#34;&gt;Selamat Datang 🎉&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ini pos pertama saya menggunakan &lt;strong&gt;Hugo PaperMod&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo cepat dan ringan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PaperMod cantik dan minimal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rusdyahmad&#34;&gt;Saya di GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
