<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Development on RA</title><link>https://rusdy.com/categories/development/</link><description>Recent content in Development on RA</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.149.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rusdy.com/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Claude Code: How I Save More Time for Family</title><link>https://rusdy.com/posts/claude-code-saving-time-for-family/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rusdy.com/posts/claude-code-saving-time-for-family/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Been coding for 23 years now. Love it, always have. But man, sometimes the boring stuff just eats up all my time. Then I found Claude Code, and wow – suddenly I can build way more cool stuff AND actually have dinner with my family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Claude Code Interface" loading="lazy" src="https://rusdy.com/claude_code.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-problem-too-much-time-on-boring-stuff"&gt;The Problem: Too Much Time on Boring Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look, after all these years, setting up databases and writing the same login code for the hundredth time isn&amp;rsquo;t fun anymore. It&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip; tedious. I&amp;rsquo;d rather spend that time:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>LaraText: Simplifying Translation Management in Laravel Applications</title><link>https://rusdy.com/posts/laratext-laravel-translation-package/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rusdy.com/posts/laratext-laravel-translation-package/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Managing translations in Laravel applications can be a tedious and error-prone process, especially when dealing with multiple languages and dynamic content. Enter &lt;strong&gt;LaraText&lt;/strong&gt; by Eduardo Lázaro — an elegant package that revolutionizes how we handle internationalization in Laravel projects by combining simplicity, automation, and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-translation-challenge"&gt;The Translation Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional Laravel translation management often involves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating and maintaining separate language files for each locale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manually writing translation keys that are hard to read and maintain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time-consuming process of translating content across multiple languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping track of missing translations across different language files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LaraText tackles these challenges head-on with an intuitive approach that makes translation keys both &lt;strong&gt;useful and readable&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Managing Model Ownership in Laravel with the Ownable Package</title><link>https://rusdy.com/posts/laravel-ownable-package/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rusdy.com/posts/laravel-ownable-package/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Need a clean, reusable solution to handle ownership dynamics in your Laravel app? Enter &lt;strong&gt;Laravel Ownable&lt;/strong&gt; — a polished package by Abdullah Sowailem that lets any Eloquent model own any other model. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re managing users and tasks, vendors and products, or documents with dynamic custodians, this package brings clarity, flexibility, and auditability to ownership logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a refreshed overview for your blog, incorporating up-to-date insights from the official repository (updated August 10, 2025).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>